

Aditi Ashok Ingale

♦ Chemnitz, Germany **a** aditiingale20001946@gmail.com

L +49 155 6067 9978 **in** LinkedIn **⊘** Portfolio **□** GitHub

I'm a curious software engineer with over 2 years of experience building apps that work, scale, and make life easier. I've worked on everything from automation tools to cloud based systems, and I'm always up for solving problems and learning something new along the way.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java | JavaScript | Python | SQL | C++ | PHP | Bash

Frameworks: Spring Boot | React | Angular | Streamlit | Node.js | Next.js

Tools & DevOps: Jenkins | Git | CI/CD | JIRA | ServiceNow | Power BI | Docker | Postman | Confluence

Data & Analytics: Power BI | Tableau | Pandas | NumPy | Scikit-learn | SQL Databases

Methodologies: Agile | Scrum | DevOps | GitOps

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Analyst, Capgemini

09/2022 - 05/2024 | Pune, India

- Developed scalable microservices-based enterprise applications using Java (Spring Boot) and Angular (TypeScript).
- Worked with RESTful APIs, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, and Git in Agile environments.
- Integrated JIRA and ServiceNow for task synchronization through automation tooling.
- Created dashboards and reports in Power BI for insights-driven decision-making.

Trainee Software Developer, Capgemini

01/2022 - 04/2022 | Pune, India

- Designed and implemented REST APIs, ensuring seamless system communication and integration.
- Optimized performance in cloud-based test environments using AWS, Citrix, Virtual Labs, and O365.
- Worked in Agile teams with Jenkins CI/CD, improving deployment efficiency.

Software Development Intern, Neuronode Technologies

07/2021 - 09/2021 | Remote, India

- Built a real-time stock analysis app using Python, Streamlit and Quandl API.
- Enabled dynamic stock tracking and real-time profit/loss analysis through interactive visualizations.

EDUCATION

Master of Science - Web Engineering,

Technische Universität Chemnitz

10/2024 - present | Germany

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer,

Savitribai Phule Pune University

07/2018 – 04/2022 | India

PROJECTS

- Detection of Price Variations of consumable commodities using Social Media and News Bidirectional Encoder Representations (Bert) a deep learning model, Data Prediction and Data Analysis
- Shopping Cart System and Hospital Management System

Angular, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Swagger, Microservices, Nodejs, MySQL, Java, Postman and OAuth

• Speech to Sign Language Convertor

JavaScript, Speech Recognition, Data Analysis And Web Speech API

CERTIFICATIONS

LANGUAGES

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner AWS
- Generative AI Essentials AWS
- Agile Software Development Coursera
- English CI
- German Bi